♪ It seems today
that all you see ♪
♪ Is violence in movies
and sex on TV ♪
♪ But where are those
good old-fashioned values ♪
♪ On which we used to rely? ♪
♪ Lucky there's a family guy ♪
♪ Lucky there's a man
who positively can do ♪
♪ All the things that make us ♪
♪ Laugh and cry ♪
♪ He's... a...
Fam... ily... Guy! ♪
Hey, everyone.
You'll never guess
who I ran into
at the market just now.
Your hairdresser who's
almost dead from cancer?
Ross Fishman.
Your old boyfriend?
The one with the penis?
Peter, would you stop
being so jealous?
I dated Ross 20 years ago.
That's right.
And that means he had
you first, Lois.
I'll always be Scottie Pippen
to his Michael Jordan.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Michael Jordan!
(cheering)
And Scottie Pippen.
(scattered clapping)
FAN:
He's also good.
FAN 2:
Why didn't they do Jordan last?
FAN 1:
Alphabetical?
FAN 2:
Oh, right. That's smart.
You're smart.
But still.
Peter, don't be ridiculous.
Ross' wife was with him,
and in fact,
they invited us all over
for dinner tonight.
Oh, come on, Lois.
I hate that guy.
I don't want to have dinner with him.
Hey!
It's cooked food
in another house.
That's exciting for
life-over women like me.
We're going.
All right, fine.
But I'm gonna stare at
his wife's boobs so hard
that when they both go
into the kitchen together,
it will be discussed.
Ah, the cold car ride through
a dark, suburban night.
Look out the window and
think of death, kids.
It's a-comin'.
Wow, Pam.
Everything smells terrific.
Did you make all
of this yourself?
Yeah, I just got home from work,
put down the lawyer's briefcase,
and put on the chef's hat.
You know how it is.
Nah. She don't do nothing.
So, Peter, Lois tells me that
you're working at the brewery.
I think that's great.
A real job.
Trading futures,
that's not real.
But the money is unreal.
Hey. To real jobs.
That's it, Fishman.
Shirts off.
I want to see who's
got bigger pecs.
Peter!
Well, they look better
when they're oiled up.
Pass the salad dressing.
Oh, no, it's an almost-empty
squeeze bottle.
Hang on.
Eh, it's all out.
There's dressing on that salad.
Give me that salad.
Yeah, who's
the better man now, Ross?
Brian, what are you
doing down there?
They didn't set
a place for me.
Not a dog family.
Oh.
G'way.
G'way, you.
So, Ben, do you go
to James Woods High?
(chortling):
No.
I'm a junior
at The Meadows.
It's a private school.
Oh, do they do it so right
at The Meadows.
Class size is so small.
And they really
know your child.
They care.
Mr. Wiggins rested his thing
on Jen Crosby's shoulder
during a test.
Yes, I'm told James Woods High
leads the nation
in teacher-to-student
"thing resting."
Well, it's family
that really matters,
and no family is
closer than ours.
That's why we love
taking trips together.
Here we are in Machu Picchu.
Is that the topless place
in South Attleboro?
I spat on a chick there
at a work retreat.
Peter, just stop talking.
What? We been places.
They ain't so great.
Well, this year is perhaps
our biggest trip ever.
We're climbing
Mount Everest.
Oh, yeah?
Is that right?
Well, so are we!
We are?
Peter, I highly doubt that.
I mean, no offense,
but it doesn't look like
your family would
be up to the task.
I think he's right about that.
After all, we couldn't even
turn a double play.
All right, Griffins, on the
ground, we're going to second.
Let's turn two here.
Ground ball's
a double play ball.
Play's at second.
Let's look sharp.
Tough "D." Tough "D."
Let's flash that leather.
Head in the game.
Play's to second.
This infield is
the Great Wall of China:
nothing's getting past us.
Good "D" behind you, Bri.
Good "D" all around.
(bat cracks against ball)
(in Stewie's voice):
I'm okay, everyone.
Don't worry, I am okay.
My voice sounds weird,
this is weird, I know,
but I feel fine.
Man, what a bunch of jerks.
Yeah, we should call
Ross and tell him,
"This is the hospital,
and your mom's dead."
And then, he'll be like,
"What hospital?"
And we'll be like,
"Saint Up Yours,"
and then... and then
that's, like, two jokes.
Look, I'm sorry, Lois.
I-I know we can't
climb Mount Everest.
I-It's just, that guy
really got to me,
and I wanted to
stick it to him.
Will you call tomorrow
and make some excuse
that doesn't
make me look bad?
Ooh, I know.
Tell him I'm a
pathological liar
and that I've been
under a lot of stress
because of the child
rape charges I'm facing.
I think we should do it.
What?
Lois, you can't be serious.
Oh, I'm dead serious.
You think I liked sitting there
pretending to be polite
to those people while they
talked down to us like that?
Well, I'm sick of it.
I'm sick of this family
always feeling second best.
I want to do something
we can be proud of.
I want Stewie,
Meg, and Chris
to grow up
with some confidence.
Then don't buy our shoes
at the car wash.
But climbing the world's
most dangerous mountain?
Isn't that a little extreme?
Maybe.
But if the Fishmans
can do it, so can we.
Yeah, we're just as good as them
or any other family.
That's right.
You guys, we're
climbing Mount Everest.
Let's do it!
Yay! I drank seven cups
of coffee at the Fishmans'!
(knocking)
Oh, crap. It's Quagmire.
I don't want him
knowing about this.
He's always trying
to horn in on our plans.
QUAGMIRE:
Hey, what's going on?
You guys up to something?
Shh-shh, kids, don't move.
(doorknob rattling)
Hello?
(knocking)
So we're really doing this?
We're actually gonna
climb Mount Everest?
How are you okay with this?
Well, if we make it
to the summit,
I could pee there,
and then it would be mine.
'Cause the rule is,
the highest pee wins.
Okay, gang, once
we arrive in Nepal,
we'll get all the supplies we
need for the trip up Everest.
Okay, but remember, kids,
the people there have
never seen people before.
So when they walk up to you,
quickly stuff a dollar bill
in their mouth.
And then you can pet 'em
as much as you want.
Is that true, Dad?
Nah, truth is, I don't know
nothing about this place.
I don't even know
why it's called Nepal.
The mountains
look like nipples.
Well, you can't just
call a country Nipples.
What about Nepal?
Ooh, I like that.
Ha.
Shocker: God gets it right.
(car horns honking)
(bicycle bells ringing)
Okay, now, we got to make sure
we've got all the provisions
before we head
up to base camp.
'Cause I don't think there's
gonna be a Star Market
halfway up the mountain.
(all laughing)
Oh, Mom.
That's our local
market at home.
Okay, let's split up
and meet in an hour
in front of The Yak Shack.
And my mom is pounding
on the door,
and I'm like,
"Mom, don't come in here.
I'm yakking off."
MAN:
Boo.
So, I've been carrying this
really promiscuous guide around,
and my back starts itching.
I go to the doctor,
turns out I got sherpies.
PETER:
Ha-ha!
Yeah, I'll meet
you guys here.
I'm just gonna be here.
Peter, I don't think we need
a donkey for this climb.
Of course we don't
need a donkey, Lois.
It's a status thing here.
You, leather man.
You sell me donkey.
I don't know what it is,
but you... have got... it.
(all gasp)
Oh, my God.
It's enormous.
Lois, this is probably a
terrible time to remember this,
but I think I might have
left the weed whacker on.
(engine revving)
Well, look who's here.
I didn't believe you'd actually
follow through with this.
Oh, hey, Fishman.
Hey, listen, on
a scale of one to ten,
how bad is the bathroom
situation up here?
Like, ten is a suite
at the Four Seasons,
and one is
a tied-up raincoat sleeve
at a party in your honor.
Yes, we're here, Ross.
When our family says that
we're gonna do something,
we follow through
with it.
Yeah, in fact, not only
are we gonna climb it,
we are gonna beat
you guys to the top.
(chuckles)
I seriously
doubt that.
Oh, yeah?
Well, so do I!
Yeah, so you watch it, Fishman.
We are gonna beat you so bad,
you'll think you gave
Chris Brown an STD.
Is that what happened?
You're not gonna
beat us to the top.
In fact, you probably won't
even climb Everest at all.
You don't have the nerve.
Like hell I don't.
Getting to the top
ahead of you
is gonna be one of the
greatest moments of my life.
It might even beat graduating
from chiropractor school.
Robert Baker.
Brad O'Bannon.
Anyone.
Okay, the Fishmans are
heading up the North Face,
but I've been studying
this map
and I think we've got a better
chance of beating them
if we go
up the South Face.
Oh, we don't need
a map, Brian.
I got us a GPMS machine.
WOMAN (annoyed):
Go up.
What do you think?
Just go up.
Sorry.
Okay, can everyone
just stop freaking out
and just give me,
like, two minutes?
God!
(crying):
Everyone's always yelling at me.
W... All the questions!
All right, well, maybe
we'll turn you on later
and see how you feel.
She was so nice
in the store.
Well, come on, everyone,
let's get started.
(shuddering)
Brian, I'm not sure
I can do this.
It's chillier out here
than Angelina Jolie.
Something like that.
I-I-I don't know,
I-I-I'm so cold.
She took that sad
old lady's husband.
You're just gonna have to
block out the cold, Stewie.
Picture yourself
in a warm place.
(breathes deeply)
Okay, I think I can do that.
♪ Do you remember ♪
♪ The 21st night of September? ♪
♪ Love was changing
the minds of pretenders ♪
♪ While chasing
the clouds away ♪
♪ Our hearts were ringing ♪
♪ In the key that
our souls were singing ♪
♪ As we danced in the night ♪
♪ Remember ♪
♪ How the stars stole
the night away ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Ba de ya ♪
♪ Say, do you remember ♪
♪ Dancing in September? ♪
♪ Ba de ya ♪
♪ Never was a cloudy day... ♪
♪ ♪
Do you want the
heat on, sir?
Yes, please.
♪ ♪
Oh, my God.
How are we supposed
to get across this?
W-We have to walk
on those ladders?
Guys, be sure to look
down the whole time.
It's really deep
and freaky and disorienting.
(screaming)
(thud)
Peter! Oh, my God!
Dad!
It's okay! There's a huge pile
of dead bodies down here
that cushioned my fall!
Do any of them seem
like they have
any extra tampons
in their backpack?
Uh, no!
"No," like you checked
and there aren't any, "no"?
Or "no," you're
just assuming?
I-I'm embarrassed.
(shuddering)
Peter, you left
the flap open.
It's like a thousand
degrees in here, Lois.
Close the tent now!
It's freezing!
Headline: "Woman Cold."
(all panting)
My God.
I think I see the Fishmans.
They're down on that ridge.
We're ahead of them!
Well, then
let's keep moving.
You guys,
we can do this.
We can beat them!
Hey, you know, I heard, when
you drink at high altitude,
it hits you even faster.
Whoo! Party!
I love you guys!
You don't know
how much you mean to me.
You think you're better than me?
Why can't you hit a curveball?
(sobbing):
I've done nothing with my life!
Hey, cats, is
everybody cool?
Sammy Davis Jr.?
What are you doing up here?
Whatever Frank tells
me to do, man.
Hey, Sam, get back in here
and carry my golf clubs.
Yas, boss!
(laughs)
Ew. Seems kind of racist,
doesn't it?
No, no, 'cause,
'cause Sammy's in on it.
Okay...
But he's still
carrying the clubs.
This is so hard!
I can't do
this, Mom!
Come on!
Keep pushing, kids!
We're almost there!
I'm feeling nauseous.
I think I got altitude sickness.
Hey, Brian, you want
a pukesicle?
I would love a pukesicle.
(gasps) I can see
the top of the mountain!
Let's move it!
We made it!
I don't believe it!
We climbed Mount Everest!
Isn't it amazing, Brian?
You can see for...
Oh, you're doing
your pee thing, right.
I don't really know
what the point is.
I mean, there's no way
other dogs can smell this.
Trust me, Stewie.
They'll know.
They'll know
the world is now mine.
(sniffs)
(bleep) no way.
Oh, my God, you guys.
I'm so proud
of us all!
We made it!
We proved that
we're not second-best!
ROSS: Well, look
who finally got here.
You, you beat us?
Don't feel too bad, gang.
We only beat you by one hour,
12 minutes, and 43 seconds.
And, quite frankly,
we're bored of it up here.
So you guys enjoy it.
We're gonna head back down.
I hate those guys.
Yeah, me, too.
Come on.
Let's head back down.
At least the hard part's over.
I'm not so sure
about that.
You might want to take a
look at those storm clouds.
(thunder rumbles)
Oh, my God.
Yeah, it looks like
it's closing in fast.
We're all gonna die!
All right, everyone get
into a hilarious pose,
so when they dig out
our bodies,
they'll have a good laugh.
Heh. This guy's
pretty funny.
This is terrible!
The storm keeps
getting worse!
Mom, I can't even see!
And the scarf Brian
called "a gay waste"
makes a rather
important appearance.
I'm so hungry.
Me, too.
I don't know
if I can keep going.
Peter, I still
don't understand.
How the hell can we
already be out of food?
Didn't I tell you
to bring trail mix?
Yeah, but by that
I thought you meant
a set list of totally awesome
tunes, which I do have.
♪ I got the power! ♪
And after this, it's
"Everybody Dance Now"
and after that, it's
"Come Baby Come."
That sounds
like Jock Jams.
It is similar
to Jock Jams.
It is Jock Jams.
You guys, look,
there's something up ahead.
I think it's a person.
Oh, my God,
maybe they have food.
Maybe it's a rescue team.
Oh, my God,
it's Ben Fishman.
Is he...?
Yep. He's dead.
Oh, great. Not only are we
caught in this blizzard,
but there's some maniac up here
freezing people to death.
That poor boy.
We should bury him.
It's only right.
Yeah, yeah, we should, Lois.
You're right.
Or we could...
Could what?
Eat him.
(all gasp)
Brian!
Look, if we don't eat something
soon, we're all gonna pass out
from exhaustion and freeze
to death just like him.
Are we really
considering this?
We're talking
about eating a person.
Yeah, I'm not so sure
about this.
Oh, I thought
we decided.
I'm sorry.
Well... I guess
we don't have a choice.
I am oddly prepared for this.
Oh, God, Peter.
I hope Ben would forgive
us for what we did.
Look, we needed to eat,
the same way birds need to fly.
What do you mean, you don't have
our names on there?
My wife and I absolutely have
to be on this flight.
I'm doing the best
I can, sir.
Do you have
your confirmation number?
I think you'll find all the
information you need on here.
Sir, this is just
a piece of paper
with the word "south"
written on it.
Can I speak to your supervisor?
You guys, there's
someone up ahead.
Ben?!
Oh, my God, it's
the Fishmans.
They look terrible.
(wearily):
Have you seen Ben?
We lost him
in the storm.
We're headed back up
to find him.
I just hope he's not trapped
in some crevice somewhere.
Well, my gut tells me
he'll be squeezing himself out
of a crevice very soon.
Oh! We finally made
it below the storm.
Look! I see base camp!
Yay!
We're gonna be okay!
(thunder crashing)
Wait! We have to go back.
What? What are you
talking about?
Kids, your mom is clearly
delirious from the altitude.
I say we leave her
behind and marry
that hot new assistant
from my work.
Look, Ben freezing to
death was one thing.
We had nothing
to do with that.
But we just let Ross and
Pam walk back up there,
probably to
their deaths.
And you know what?
That's not who we are.
We're the Griffins.
And you know how we win?
You know how we keep
from being second-best?
We do the right thing.
We go back up there
and save them.
Tell me again why we ate
a person before we ate the dog.
(sighs) Your mom's right.
Let's head
back up there.
Plus, if we don't rescue
the Fishmans,
their Jewish god is
just gonna sit there
and make us feel guilty.
You do... whatever you want.
(sniffing)
Over here!
I think I smell 'em!
Oh, my God!
Look down there!
We got to get them out!
They'll die down there!
Well, we've got some rope.
(ice cracking)
Quick, Peter!
You're the only one strong
enough to carry two people.
(gasping)
(grunting)
All right, I got 'em!
Pull me up!
(all grunting)
Peter, we can't do it!
You're too heavy!
Keep going!
You're almost there!
I found a rock I like.
Griffins, I don't know
how to thank you.
We never would have made it
without your help.
Oh, you would've done
the same for us.
There are more important things
than a petty rivalry.
We're just happy
that you're okay.
PAM: Well, thank you both.
You saved our lives.
And Peter, I'll never
forget what you did for us.
You're a good man.
All right, you rest up, get better,
we ate your son. Bring it up!
Thank you for watching "Family Guy" on
www.FOX-fan.ru